JULIET VARGHESE

Email id: julietvargese@gmail.com

Phone no: +91 9718488547

Career Objective

A systematic, hard working team player, of more than 2 years of experience with a Bachelors Degree in Journalism and Mass Communication and Post Graduate Diploma in Advertising and Public Relations. Highly motivated to constantly develop my skills and grow professionally.

Professional Experience

Executive -Marketing & Public Relations at Nuberg Engineering Ltd (March 2020- June 2020)

- Assisting in planning and development of PR plans to support the engagement activities of the organization
- Drafting press releases and media pitch notes and media dissemination
- Media Relations
- Client Servicing

Public Relations Executive at M D Niche Media Consultants (August 2017 - February 2020)

- Assisting in planning, developing and implementing various media action plans to support key engagement activities within the overall PR plan
- Organizing and managing client related media coverage in an efficient manner
- Media Relations
- Preparing reports on client related media
- Generating coverage for press releases in the right media, based on an intimate understanding of the industry, media needs, and client objectives
- Communicating with clients and media, and respond to their requests in the right manner

Clients Handled: Kerala Tourism; Trivandrum, Kerala, Kathakar International Storytellers Festival 2018 & 2019, Sahapedia; New Delhi, Kochi Muziris Biennale; Kochi, Kerala, India and the World Exhibition: National Museum, New Delhi, National Institute for Speech and Hearing; Trivandrum, Kerala

Internship

POWERGRID Corporation India Ltd in Corporate Communication Department

- Assisted Seniors in planning, developing and implementing PR Plans and crisis management plans
- Organized Press Conference and Exhibitions and Prepared Brand Building Activities for POWERGRID Corporation of India Limited for six months.

Educational Qualifications

DIRECTORATE OF DISTANCE EDUCATION GURU JAMBESHWAR UNIVERSITY, HISAR

Post Graduate Diploma in Advertising and Public Relations 2018-2019, 71%

MANAV RACHNA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY, FARIDABAD

Bachelors in Journalism and Mass Communication 2014-2017, 7.10 CGPA

St. PAUL'S SCHOOL, HAUS KHAZ

Higher Secondary School 2013-2014, 71.8%

St. JOHN'S SCHOOL, KERALA

Senior Secondary 2011-2012, 94%

Skills

Interpersonal skills, Communication Skills, Quick Learner, Creative Writing Skills, Presentation Skills, Time Management Skills

Hobbies

Singing, Reading novels and spiritual books, Drawing, Painting, Watching movies

Achievements & Extra-Curricular Activities

Secured Third position in Mock Parliament conducted by Faculty of Media Studies in Manav Rachna University.

Secured First position in Monoact at School level

Glorified with the title of Campus Star by Radio Manay Rachna 107.8 FM

Organized and Participated in Theatre and Cultural society events at Deans Student Welfare, Manav Rachna University

Volunteered in Asia Olympics Pre Qualifying Competition in Shooting (by National Rifle Association of India).

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 04 November 1996

Father's Name: Varghese P

Mother's Name: Sheeba Varghese

Address: 36- MIG, Suraj Apartments, Pul Prahaladpur, New Delhi -110044, India

Declaration

All the above data provided is correct up to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 20.07.2020 JULIET VARGHESE